<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<component type="desktop">
  <id>kalzium.desktop</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-2.0+</project_license>
  <name>Kalzium</name>
  <name xml:lang="cs">Kalzium</name>
  <name xml:lang="es">Kalzium</name>
  <name xml:lang="fi">Kalzium</name>
  <name xml:lang="fr">Kalzium</name>
  <name xml:lang="lt">Kalzium</name>
  <name xml:lang="nds">Kalzium</name>
  <name xml:lang="nl">Kalzium</name>
  <name xml:lang="pl">Kalzium</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt">Kalzium</name>
  <name xml:lang="pt-BR">Kalzium</name>
  <name xml:lang="sk">Kalzium</name>
  <name xml:lang="sv">Kalzium</name>
  <name xml:lang="uk">Kalzium</name>
  <name xml:lang="x-test">xxKalziumxx</name>
  <name xml:lang="zh-TW">化學_Kalzium</name>
  <summary>Periodic Table of Elements</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="cs">Periodická tabulka</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="es">Tabla periódica de los elementos</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="fi">Alkuaineiden jaksollinen järjestelmä</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="fr">Classification périodique des éléments</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="lt">Periodinė elementų lentelė</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nds">Periodensysteem vun de Elementen</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="nl">Periodieke systeem der Elementen</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pl">Tablica okresowa pierwiastków</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pt">Tabela Periódica dos Elementos</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="pt-BR">Tabela Periódica dos Elementos</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sk">Periodická tabuľka prvkov</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="sv">Periodiska systemet</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="uk">Періодична таблиця елементів</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="x-test">xxPeriodic Table of Elementsxx</summary>
  <summary xml:lang="zh-TW">元素週期表</summary>
  <description>
    <p>Kalzium is a program that shows you the Periodic Table of Elements. You can use Kalzium to search for information about the elements or to learn facts about the periodic table. It provides an overview of the important data (like melting points, electron affinity, electron negativity, electron configuration, radii, mass, ionisation energy), an isotope table, and different colored views of the periodic table (separation of the different blocks, year simulator, temperature simulator). It contains tools to visualize the spectral lines of each element, a molecular weight calculator, a 3D molecule editor, and an equation solver for stoichiometric problems.</p>
    <p xml:lang="es">Kalzium es un programa que muestra la tabla periódica de los elementos. Puede usar Kalzium para buscar información sobre los elementos o para aprender cosas sobre la tabla periódica. Proporciona un resumen de los datos importantes (como el punto de fusión, la afinidad electrónica, la electronegatividad, la configuración electrónica, el radio, la masa o la energía de ionización), una tabla de isótopos y distintas vistas en color de la tabla periódica (separación de los diferentes bloques, simulador de años, simulador de temperaturas). Contiene herramientas para visualizar las líneas del espectro de cada elemento, una calculadora de pesos moleculares, un editor de moléculas en 3D y un balanceador de ecuaciones para problemas estequiométricos.</p>
    <p xml:lang="fr">Kalzium est un programme qui vous montre les tableau périodique des éléments. Vous pouvez utiliser Kalzium pour rechercher des informations sur les éléments ou pour apprendre des faits sur le tableau périodique. Il fournit une vue d'ensemble des données importantes (tels que la température de fusion, l'affinité électronique, l'électronégativité, la configuration électronique, le rayon, la mass, l'énergie d'ionisation), une table des isotopes, et différentes vues colorées du tableau périodique (séparation des différent blocs, simulateur temporel, simulateur de température). Il contient des outils pour visualiser les lignes spectrales de chaque élément, un calculateur de masse des molécules, un éditeur de molécules en 3D, et un solveur d'équation pour les problèmes stœchiométriques.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nds">Kalzium wiest Di dat Periodensysteem vun de Elementen. Mit Kalzium kannst Du wat över de Elementen lehren oder wat över dat Periodensysteem rutfinnen. Dat stellt Di en Översicht över de wichtigen Daten (as Smöltpunkt, Elektronenaffiniteet, Elektronegativiteet, Elektronentosamenstellen, Dörmaat, Mass oder Ioniserenenergie) praat, en Isotopentabell un verscheden infarvt Ansichten vun't Periodensysteem (Ünnerdelen vun de Blöck, Johrensimuleren un Temperatuursimuleren). Dat bargt en Funkschoon, mit de Du de Elementen ehr Spektraallienen ankieken kannst, en Moleköölwichtreekner, en 3D-Molekööleditor un en Gliekenlöser för stöchiometersch Problemen.</p>
    <p xml:lang="nl">Kalzium is een programma dat u het Periodieke Systeem der Elementen toont. U kunt Kalzium gebruiken om naar informatie over de elementen te zoeken of de feiten te leren over het periodieke systeem. Het biedt een overzicht van de belangrijke gegevens (zoals smeltpunts, electron affiniteit, electron negativiteit, elektronenconfiguratie, stralen, massa, ionisatie-energy), een isotopentabel en verschillende gekleurde beelden van het periodieke systeem (scheiding van de verschillende blokken, jaarsimulator, temperatuursimulator). Het bevat hulpmiddelen om de spectrale lijnen van elk element te visualiseren, een rekenmachine voor moleculair gewicht, een 3D editor voor moleculen en een oplosser van vergelijkingen voor stoichiometrische problemen.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pl">Kalzium jest programem, który wyświetla tablicę okresową pierwiastków. Kalzium można używać do znajdywania szczegółów o pierwiastkach oraz do nauki faktów o tablicy okresowej. Program zapewnia przegląd ważnych danych (takich jak: punkty topnienia, powinowactwo elektronowe, ujemność elektronów, konfigurację elektronów, promień, masę, energię jonizacji), tablicę izotopów i różne wielobarwne widoki tablicy okresowej (oddzielone różne bloki, symulator roku, symulator temperatury). Program zawiera narzędzia do wizualizacji linii widma każdego elementu, kalkulator wagi cząsteczkowej, trójwymiarowy edytor cząsteczki, program do rozwiązywania równań dla problemów stechiometrycznych.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt">O Kalzium é um programa que lhe mostra a Tabela Periódica de Elementos. Poderá usar o Kalzium para procurar por informações sobre os elementos ou para aprender factos sobre a tabela periódica. Oferece uma visão geral sobre os dados importantes (como os pontos de fusão, afinidade electrónica, negatividade electrónica, raios, massas, energias de ionização), uma tabela de isótopos e diferentes vistas coloridas da tabela periódica (separação dos diferentes blocos, simuladores de anos, simuladores de temperaturas). Contém ferramentas para visualizar as linhas espectrais de cada elemento, uma calculadora de pesos moleculares, um editor de moléculas 3D e um sistema de resolução de equações para problema estoquiométricos.</p>
    <p xml:lang="pt-BR">Kalzium é um programa que lhe mostra a Tabela Periódica dos Elementos. Você poderá usá-lo para procurar informações sobre os elementos ou para aprender fatos sobre a tabela periódica. Ele oferece um resumo com os dados importantes (como os pontos de fusão, afinidade eletrônica, eletronegatividade, configuração eletrônica, raios, massa, energia de ionização), uma tabela de isótopos e exibição da tabela periódica em diferentes padrões de cor (separação dos diferentes blocos, simulador de anos, simulador de temperaturas). Contém ferramentas para visualizar as linhas espectrais de cada elemento, uma calculadora de pesos moleculares, um editor de moléculas 3D e um sistema de resolução de equações para problemas de estequiometria.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sk">Kalzium je program, ktorý vám ukáže periodickú tabuľku prvkov. Môžete ho použiť na hľadanie informácií o prvkoch alebo na výuku faktov o periodickej tabuľke. Poskytuje prehľad dôležitých údajov (body topenia, elektrónová afinita, elektronegativita, elektrónová konfigurácia, polomery, hmotnosť, ionizačná energia), tabuľku izotopov a rôzne farebné pohľady periodickej tabuľky (oddelenie rôznych blokov, simulátor rokov, simulátor teploty). Obsahuje nástroje na vizualizáciu spektrálnych čiar každého prvku, kalkulačku molekulárnej hmotnosti, 3D editor molekúl a riešiteľ rovníc pre stechiometrické problémy.</p>
    <p xml:lang="sv">Kalzium är ett program som visar det periodiska systemet med grundämnen. Du kan använda Kalzium för att leta efter information om grundämnen, eller för att lära dig fakta om det periodiska systemet. Det tillhandahåller en översikt av viktig information (som smältpunkt, elektronaffinitet, elektronegativitet, elektronkonfiguration, radie, massa, jonisationsenergi), en isotoptabell och olika färglagda vyer av det periodiska systemet (separation av de olika blocken, årsimulering, temperatursimulering). Det innehåller verktyg för att åskådliggöra varje grundämnes spektrallinjer, en molekylviktsräknare, en tredimensionell molekyleditor och en ekvationslösare av stökiometriska problem.</p>
    <p xml:lang="uk">Kalzium — програма, за допомогою якої ви зможете працювати з періодичною таблицею елементів. Kalzium можна скористатися для пошуку даних щодо елементів та вивчення фактів, пов’язаних із періодичною таблицею. Програма надає у ваше розпорядження важливі дані щодо елементів (температури плавлення фізичних тіл з елементів, спорідненість атомів до електрона, електронегативності, конфігурації електронної хмари, радіуса атома, маси атома, енергії іонізації), таблицю ізотопів та різні режими розфарбовування періодичної таблиці (поділ на блоки, показ таблиці за роками відкриття елементів, температурою плавлення). Передбачено інструменти для показу спектральних ліній кожного з елементів, калькулятор молекулярної ваги, редактор просторового вигляду молекул та засіб розв’язування рівнянь для стехіометричних задач.</p>
    <p xml:lang="x-test">xxKalzium is a program that shows you the Periodic Table of Elements. You can use Kalzium to search for information about the elements or to learn facts about the periodic table. It provides an overview of the important data (like melting points, electron affinity, electron negativity, electron configuration, radii, mass, ionisation energy), an isotope table, and different colored views of the periodic table (separation of the different blocks, year simulator, temperature simulator). It contains tools to visualize the spectral lines of each element, a molecular weight calculator, a 3D molecule editor, and an equation solver for stoichiometric problems.xx</p>
    <p xml:lang="zh-TW">Kalzium 是一套元素週期表的應用程式。您可以用 Kalzium 搜尋關於元素的資訊與知識。它提供了元素重要資料的概要（如熔點、電子親合力、電負性、電子結構、凡德瓦半徑、質量、游離能等等），元素的同位素表，還有週期表上的不同表達方式（如發現時間、溫度狀態等等）。它也包含了一些視覺化的工具，莫耳質量計算器，立體分子編輯器，以及方程式計算器等功能。</p>
  </description>
  <url type="homepage">http://edu.kde.org/kalzium/</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://bugs.kde.org/enter_bug.cgi?format=guided&amp;product=kalzium</url>
  <url type="help">http://docs.kde.org/stable/en/kdeedu/kalzium/</url>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>http://kde.org/images/screenshots/kalzium.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <project_group>KDE</project_group>
  <provides>
    <binary>kalzium</binary>
  </provides>
</component>
