<wissen>
	<item>
		<name>State of matter</name>
		<desc>Form of a substance; dsependant on form stability and whether it takes up a definite volume: solid, liquid or gaseous. [img]e.png[/img]</desc>
		<ref>Boiling point,Melting point</ref>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Chemical Symbol</name>
		<desc>One, two, or three letter abbreviation; set through international convention.</desc>
		<ref>Element</ref>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Chromatography</name>
		<desc>Matter separation in a moving medium (mobile Phase) through differentiated absorbtion on a static medium (stationary phase).</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Distillation</name>
		<desc>Separation of a liquid solution (homogenous mix) into its component through evaporation and condensation. In a fractionary distillation the process is repeated several times in a column.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Element</name>
		<desc>Matter that can't be broken down into simpler matter. Chemical elements are cornerstones of Materials. Elements consist of atoms that consist of a nucleus of positive protons and neutral neutrons and a shell of electrons.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Emulsion</name>
		<desc>Heterogenous mix of two liquids.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Extraction</name>
		<desc>Processing a homogenous or heterogenous mix to get pure matter.</desc>
		<ref>Mix</ref>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Filtering</name>
		<desc>Separation of a solid matter from a liquid matter or gaseous matter with a filter (porous seperation wall).</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Mix</name>
		<desc>Matter consisting of differentiated matter, combined in non-set ratios. [i]Homogenous mixes[/i] have a coherent look, [i]heterogenous mixes[/i] consist of multiple phases.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Accuracy</name>
		<desc>Consisting of accidental and systematic errors.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Law of Mass Preservation</name>
		<desc>During a chemical reaction mass is neither lost nor gained. The sum mass of the material going into the reaction equals the sum of the mass of the products of the reaction.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Law of constant proportions</name>
		<desc>An alloy always contains the same elements in the same mass ration. Should two or more elements bind together then the mass ratio is constant.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Crystalization</name>
		<desc>Separation of solid, crystallic matter from a solution, or the liquid or gaseous phases.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Solution</name>
		<desc>Homogenous mix of multiple pure materials</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Mass</name>
		<desc>Measurement of an ammount of matter.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Matter</name>
		<desc>All that takes up space andhas mass.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Phase</name>
		<desc>Through chemical composition and physical attributes homogenous portion of matter, that separated from its environment in its expantion through a surface.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Precision</name>
		<desc>Expressed through standard deviation: Values given over accidental errors.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Correctness</name>
		<desc>Values given over accidental errors.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>SI-Unit</name>
		<desc>Measurement unit using International Symbols.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Significant Point</name>
		<desc>The amount of numbers in a number that are enumeration-worthy.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Standard deviation</name>
		<desc>An amount with which the precision of a measurement can be estimates.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Suspension</name>
		<desc>Heterogenous mix consisting of a liquid and solid matter.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Alloys</name>
		<desc>Pure matter consisting of multiple elements in a set ratio.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Alpha rays</name>
		<desc>Rays consisting of alpha particles, consisting of two protons and two neutrons that are emitted from the Atoms of certain radioactive elements.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Atom</name>
		<desc>Atoms are chemically unseparatable and building blocks of matter. Atoms of one kind are alled Element.</desc>
		<ref>Element</ref>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Atomic nucleus</name>
		<desc>The small, positively-charged center of an Atom, in which Protons and Neutrons are found.</desc>
		<ref>Atom</ref>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Atomic Mass</name>
		<desc>Mass of an atom, taken on a scale where the the mass of the Atom C 12u is. In elements that consist of different isotopes the mid-range mass of the isotope mix is given.</desc>
		<ref>Atom,Mass</ref>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Beta rays</name>
		<desc>Rays consisting of electrons that are emitted from Atoms of radioactive elements.</desc>
	</item>
</wissen>
