<tools>
	<item picture="uhrglas.jpg">
		<name>Watchglas</name>
		<desc>Watchglasses are round glass panes with a diameter of circa 5 - 10 cm which are used in the laboratory technics. Their border is a bit bent up so that you can fill them with little amounts of liquids in order to let them evaporate. The evaporation can be accelerated by heating the watchglass with a Bunsen burner. Watchglassen also can be used to cover petri dishes or beakers. Moreover watchglasses are suited to weigh little amounts of matter or alternatively dry them in the airing cupboard. The term watchglass is derived from the former pocket watches' protection glass which was often domed.</desc>
	</item>
	<item picture="thermometer2.jpg">
		<name>Contact Thermometer</name>
		<desc>The difference between a contact thermometer and a normal thermometer is that the contact thermometer has an electric sensor. When a set temperature is overstepped the contact thermometer tells an attached heating device to stop heating. In this way you can keep relatively exact one temperature during an experiment.</desc>
	</item>
	<item picture="exikator.jpg">
                <name>Dehydrator</name>
		<desc>A dehydrator is a laboratory apparatus which is often made of glass and serves to dry chemical matters, means for deprivation of water alternatively liquid.
                        In principle it is a glass bowl with cap which has a planar grinding so that the bowl is air tight closeable. The dehydrator's lower part is ordinarily filled with a drying agent e.g. calcium chloride, silica gel, phosphoric anhydride or sulphuric acid. On a diaphanous cartridge of plastic or ceramics above the drying agent the matter is put in order to dry.
                        The drying agent is hygroscopic that means it dehumidifies its environment and absorbs the humidity. The atmosphere in the dehydrator dryed by the drying agent dehumidifies water alternatively dissolver tself from the matter to dry.</desc>
        </item>
        <item picture="spatel.jpg">
                <name>Spattle</name>
                <desc> The spattle is a laboratory apparatus to scrape off, hackle and transport chemicals. The material they are made of (e.g. iron, titan, platinum) and their design (e.g. flat spattle or spoon spattle) can be different.</desc>
        </item>
        <item picture="wasserstrahlpumpe.jpg">
                <name>Water Jet Pump</name>
                <desc>The water jet pump has two entries and one exit and consists in principle of two pipes that are sticked into each other. At the water entry a water jet shoots under full fuel-line pressure out of a nozzle into a bit larger pipe. Thereby the water jet carries away air or fluid from the second entry. &lt;br&gt; this is caused by the negativ pressure in a drifting fluid. Thus it is an appliance of the hydrodynamic paradox. This says that objects close to drifting fluids are aspirated instead of being pushed away.</desc>
        </item>
        <item picture="brechungsmesser.jpg">
                <name>Refractometer</name>
                <desc>With a refractometer the refraction index of optical medias is determined. If the refraction index of a chemical is known it can be used after a synthesis to determine the product's pureness or to audit the synthesis' success.</desc>
        </item>
	<item picture="moerser.jpg">
		<name>Mortar</name>
		<desc>In a mortar solid matters are mechanically hackled. Also you can homogenise a mixture of e.g. salts through grating using a mortar. The thruster for levigating is called pestle.</desc>
	</item>
	<item picture="heizplatte.jpg">
		<name>Heating Coil</name>
		<desc>Heating coils are used to heat flasks and other containers. Multiple heating coils can be connected with a thermometer so that the heat will not exceed a specified temperature. It is possible to use a magnetic field inside the heating coil to stir fluids with a magnetic stirrer. This will homogenize the fluid in terms of temperature and composition.</desc>
	</item>
	<item picture="korkring.jpg">
		<name>Cork Ring</name>
		<desc>Large containers like round-bottomed flasks are placed on rings made of cork, a special soft lightweight wood with good insulating qualities to protect fragile instruments.</desc>
	</item>
	<item picture="tropftrichter.jpg">
		<name>Dropping Funnel</name>
		<desc>A dropping funnel can be used to drop precise amounts of fluid. You can control the dropping speed with a valve.</desc>
	</item>
	<item picture="scheidetrichter.jpg">
		<name>Separating Funnel</name>
		<desc>A separating funnel can be used to separate a mixture of fluids by differing density. A valve at the bottom allows you to drain the more dense fluid for transfer to another container.</desc>
	</item>
	<item picture="rg-staender.jpg">
		<name>Test Tube Rack</name>
		<desc>This rack comes in handy when you want to test many small amounts of chemicals in a row, or if you want to dry test tubes.</desc>
	</item>
	<item picture="">
		<name>Vortexer</name>
		<desc>A vortexer serves to homogenize reagents found in laboratories. The container containing liquid to be homogenized is put on a platform. The platform shakes by rotary agitation up to 3000RPM when a contact sensor is activated. This way extremely small volumes of fluid can be homogenized quickly as well. It is the opposite of a centrifuge, used to separate fluids.</desc>
	</item>
	<item picture="spritzflasche.jpg">
		<name>Wash Bottle</name>
		<desc>These bottles are used for many purposes. In most laboratories they are usually filled with water, salt acid or other commonly used fluids. They make it easy to apply the fluid if you do not need to measure a precise amount.</desc>
	</item>
	<item picture="rotationsverdampfer.jpg">
		<name>Rotary Evaporator</name>
		<desc>A rotary evaporator consists of a round flask in a bath of hot water that is designed to evaporate solvents. The flask is rotated and the solvent collects under a vacuum onto a condenser and drips into a condensate collecting flask. This way solutions can be concentrated or purified. Through an attached vacuum pump the boiling point of the fluid can be decreased.</desc>
	</item>
	<item picture="rueckflusskuehler.jpg">
		<name>Reflux Condenser</name>
		<desc>A reflux condenser subjects fluid to a process where a gas produced by heating is collected on the reflux condenser, where it is cooled until it condenses and runs back into the original fluid. Usually it is put on a round bottom flask or several neck flasks.</desc>
	</item>
	<item picture="pileusball.jpg">
		<name>Pileusball</name>
		<desc>A pileusball is used to fill pipettes. It produces a negative pressure which makes the fluid go into the pipette. If one lets air back into the ball the fluid will run out of the pipette.</desc>
	</item>
	<item picture="rg.jpg">
		<name>Test Tube</name>
		<desc>In a test tube a chemist usually performs small reactions or experiements. There are many different types of tubes. For example some have connectors, some are etched for measurements, some are hardened for durability.</desc>
	</item>
	<item picture="schutzbrille.jpg">
		<name>Protective Goggles</name>
		<desc>Most laboratories insist that everyone wears protective goggles. Without them, it is too risky to work with most chemicals. Usually, the lens is a special type plastic which protects you from both mechanical impacts along with acid and base chemicals.</desc>
	</item>
	<item picture="rundkolben.jpg">
		<name>Round-bottomed Flask</name>
		<desc>A round-bottomed flask is used for a lot of reactions. Some can be connected to other items, as the frosting on the neck shows. With cork rings they can be placed on a table.</desc>
	</item>
	<item picture="vollpipette.jpg">
		<name>Full Pipette</name>
		<desc>Unlike a regular pipette, a full pipette only has one marking for a specific volume.</desc>
	</item>
	<item picture="trockenrohr.jpg">
		<name>Drying Tube</name>
		<desc>There are reactions which need to be kept free of water. To make this possible one uses a drying tube. In it there is a hygroscopic chemical which will absorb all water.</desc>
	</item>
	<item picture="rg-halter.jpg">
		<name>Test tube fastener</name>
		<desc>With a test tube fastener you can easily hold test tubes. If you use a fastener there is a safe distance between the hand and the test tube and the tube can be hot. In particular, it is used when you hold a test tube over an open flame.</desc>
	</item>
	<item picture="messzylinder.jpg">
		<name>Graduate</name>
		<desc>In a graduate you can fill amounts of liquids relatively precisely. Furthermore, a graduate serves to let particulate matter sink. Following this, you can separate particulates from the fluid by decanting.</desc>
	</item>
	<item picture="thermometer.jpg">
		<name>Thermometer</name>
		<desc>With a thermometer you can determine the temperature. In a laboratory special thermometers are used, which can also be used within acids or bases.</desc>
	</item>
	<item picture="ruehrfisch.jpg">
		<name>Magnetic stir bar</name>
		<desc>Magnetic stir bars are highly chemically inert, small magnetic bars. Most heaters have a built-in magnet which can rotate. Through this rotation the magnetic stir bars are spun and the solution the magnetic stir bar is in is homogenized.</desc>
	</item>
	<item picture="">
		<name>Magnetic Stir Bar Retriever</name>
		<desc>With a magnetic stir bar retriever you can remove magnetic stir bars from a pot. The retriever is a bar with a magnet at the end which attracts the stir bars.</desc>
	</item>
	<item picture="pipette.jpg">
		<name>Pipette</name>
		<desc>Pipettes serve to dose liquids in laboratories. On a pipette there is a volume scale. As a rule pileusballs are used as pipettors. Both sorts of pipettes are adjusted to fluids with a temperature of 20°C and to outflow (Ex.). If needed times of outflow are indicated on the pipettes.</desc>
	</item>
	<item picture="erlenmeyerkolben.jpg">
		<name>Erlenmeyer Flask</name>
		<desc>This flask named after the chemist Emil Erlenmeyer (1825-1909) comes - unlike the beaker - with an inverted conical base with a cylindrical neck. There are different types of erlenmeyer flasks in the laboratory application, the narrow and wide neck form and depending on the application also flasks with a normed grinding.
			&lt;br&gt;
			Through the narrowing neck the danger that fluids escape uncontrolled of the flask while addition of matter, brandishing, stiring or boiling is explicit smaller than by a beaker.
			&lt;br&gt;
			So you can in an Erlenmeyer flask easily e.g. mix fluids or accelerate solution processes by - also relatively keenly - stiring or brandishing. He also is suited - like the round-bottomed flask - for the magnetic stirrer but can be put directly because of his flat bottom. (The round-bottomed flask whereas needs a cork ring or a stage for a safe stand, the latter makes brandishing with the hand or checking by holding into back light impossible.)</desc>
	</item>
	<item picture="">
		<name>Ultrasonic Bath</name>
		<desc>For some chemical reactions it is important that the dissolver is gas free. To achieve this the reaction vessel is put for some time into a ultrasonic bath. Through the high sound frequency the vapour locks peel away and ascend. This procedure is called outgassing.</desc>
	</item>
	<item picture="waage.jpg">
		<name>Scales</name>
		<desc>In a laboratory you often have to weigh out very precise amounts of reagents. High precise scales can measure masses down to 1/10000 gram.Therefor they stand on granite blocks to avoid vibrancies and are protected against blasts by a dome.</desc>
	</item>
	<item picture="destillierbruecke.jpg">
		<name>Distillation bridge</name>
		<desc>To separate a mixture you can use distillation amongst others. The distillation bridge is thereby the way between the two pots. In the one pot there is the mixture to be separated. Through heating, a gas forms which is lead through the bridge. At the end of the bridge the gas phase is condensed again and drips in a round flask. As a rule, the bridge is cooled by return flow. In addition, there is often a thermometer for controlling the temperature on the distillation bridge.</desc>
	</item>
	<!-- proofreaders: start here! -->
	<item picture="kolbenprober.png">
		<name>Syringe</name>
		<desc>A syringe consists of two parts: A glass tube and a punch. Both are normally made of glass. A gas floats into the glass tube. As the syringe is a closed system the punch has to give way. This can be used measuring the volume of an reaction.</desc>
	</item>
	<item picture="verteiler.jpg">
		<name>Separation Beaker</name>
		<desc>At the four ends of this separation beaker you put four small caps. While distilling, you can turn the beaker by 60 degree after a certain temperate has been reached. This way, at the end of the distillation all four caps have a specific liquid in it, depending on the boiling points of the liquid distilled.</desc>
	</item>
	<item picture="brenner.jpg">
		<name>Burner</name>
		<desc>There are several types of burners. The picture shows a Teclu-Burner. Each type has specific uses. They vary in the peak temperature and overall heating capability.</desc>
	</item>
	<!-- to be proofread from this comment on! -->
	<item picture="abzug.jpg">
		<name>Extractor Hood</name>
		<desc>Most laboratories use extractor hoods. They filter the gasses from chemical reactions and pump the cleaned air outside of the building.</desc>
	</item>
	<item picture="thermometer2.jpg">
		<name>Contact Thermometer</name>
		<desc>A contact thermometer is different from a regular thermometer because of its sensor for the current temperature. Such a thermometer is connected with a heating coild. If the sensor notices that the aimed temperature has been reached the contact thermometer will make the heating coild stop heating. Therefore in an experiment it is possible to have a constant temperature.</desc>
	</item>
	<item picture="halter.jpg">
		<name>Clamps</name>
		<desc>With clamps as used in a laboratory you can easily hold all kinds of tools.</desc>
	</item>
	<item picture="phpapier.jpg">
		<name>Litmus Paper</name>
		<desc>There are multiple way to measure the pH-Value of an solution. With a litmus paper it is easy to get a pretty precise pH-Value. The color indicates the value. If you need a more precise value you can for example use a pH-Meter which is using the conductivity of a solution.</desc>
	</item>
	<item picture="trichter.jpg">
		<name>Short-stem Funnel</name>
		<desc>A funnel is used in the laboratory to fill powder into something.</desc>
	</item>
	<item picture="">
		<name>Buret</name>
		<desc>A buret is used to titrate liquids. The buret is filled with a specified volume of a liquid. Below it a container |||the word container is not good here. You place any kind of "glas" under it...||| like an Erlenmeyer flask is placed. By opening the valve the liquid in the container will be titrated. High-quality buret have a venting-mechanism with which they can be very easily refilled with the exact volume for which the buret is calibrated.</desc>
	</item>
	<item picture="becherglas.jpg">
		<name>Beaker</name>
		<desc>Beakers are used in many places for a lot of tasks. They are used to store chemicals are to perform chemical reactions. They are also often used for titrations.</desc>
	</item>
	<item picture="dsc.jpg">
		<name>DSC (Differencial Scanning Calorimetry)</name>
		<desc>The DSC measures the heat flow volume of a compound. This value is very specific for every kind of matter. Thus, the DSC is used to identify chemicals or to describe them.</desc>
	</item>
	<item picture="">
		<name>Dewar vessel</name>
		<desc>a dewar vessel (or dewar flask) is designed for a good thermal insulation. Its hull is a double-layer construction with vacuum between the two layers. Because of this they are appropriote for keeping liquids cold or warm. A thermos flawsk is an example of a dewar vessel.</desc>
	</item>
</tools>
