<tools>
	<tool picture="heizplatte.jpg">
		<name>Heating Coil</name>
		<desc>Heating coils are used to heat flasks and other containers. Multiple heating coils can be connected with a thermometer so that the heat wont exceed a specified temperature. It is possible to use a magnetic field inside the heating coil to stir fluids with a magnetic stirrer. This will homogenize the fluid in terms of temperature and composition.</desc>
	</tool>
	<tool picture="korkring.jpg">
		<name>Cork Ring</name>
		<desc>Large containers like round-bottomed flasks are placed on rings made of cork.</desc>
	</tool>
	<tool picture="tropftrichter.jpg">
		<name>Dropping Funnel</name>
		<desc>A dropping funnel can be used to drop precise amounts of fluid. You can control the dropping speed with a valve.</desc>
	</tool>
	<tool picture="scheidetrichter.jpg">
		<name>Separating Funnel</name>
		<desc>A separating funnel can be used to separate a mixture of fluids by differing density. A valve at the bottom allows you to drain the more dense fluid for transfer to another container.</desc>
	</tool>
	<tool picture="rg-staender.jpg">
		<name>Test Tube Rack</name>
		<desc>This rack comes in handy if you want to test a lot of small amounts of checmicals in a row, or if you want to dry test tubes.</desc>
	</tool>
	<tool picture="">
		<name>Vortexer</name>
		<desc>A vortexer serves to homogenise reagents found in laboratories. The container containing liquid to be homogenised is put on a platform. The platform shakes by rotary agitation up to 3000RPM when a contact sensor is activated. This way extremely small volumes of fluid can be homogenised quickly as well.</desc>
	</tool>
	<tool picture="spritzflasche.jpg">
		<name>Wash Bottle</name>
		<desc>These bottles are used for a lot of purposes. In most laboratories you will find water, salt acid or other commonly used fluids in them. They make it easy to access the fluid if the amount you use is not that important.</desc>
	</tool>
	<tool picture="rotationsverdampfer.jpg">
		<name>Rotary Evaporator</name>
		<desc>A rotary evaporator consists of a round flask into a bath of hot water. The flask is rotating whereby the dissolver forms a thin film. This one evaporates and condenses again in a reflux condenser. The condensate is intercepted in an other pot. That way solutions can be concentrated and/ or cleaned. Through a affliated vacuum pump the fluid's boiling point can be decreased again.</desc>
	</tool>
	<tool picture="rueckflusskuehler.jpg">
		<name>Reflux Condenser</name>
		<desc>A reflux condenser serves to anneal a gas phase during an experiment. As a rule it is put on round-bottom or several neck flasks. Gas which arise from heat addition attain to the reflux condenser, whose walls are rinsed thoroughly with cold water. Thereby the gas is refrigerated. Finally it condenses and attains back to the room of reaction.</desc>
	</tool>
	<tool picture="pileusball.jpg">
		<name>Pileusball</name>
		<desc>A pileusball is used to fill pipettes. It produces a negative pressure which makes the fluid go into the pipette. If one lets air back into the ball the fluid will run out of the pipette.</desc>
	</tool>
	<tool picture="rg.jpg">
		<name>Test Tube</name>
		<desc>In test tube a chemist usually performs small reaktions. There a lots of differnet tubs, for example those with and without grinding.</desc>
	</tool>
	<tool picture="schutzbrille.jpg">
		<name>Protective Goggles</name>
		<desc>Most labarotories insist that everyone is wearing protective gooles. Without them it is to risky to work with most chemicals. Usually, their glass is some kind of specific plastic which protects you from mechanical impats as well as acids and bases.</desc>
	</tool>
	<tool picture="rundkolben.jpg">
		<name>Round-bottomed Flask</name>
		<desc>A round-bottomed flask is used for a lot of reaktions. They can be connected to other items, most of them are grinded. With corc rings they can be placed on a table.</desc>
	</tool>
	<tool picture="vollpipette.jpg">
		<name>Full Pipette</name>
		<desc>Unlike a regular pipette, a full pipette only has one marking for a specific volume.</desc>
	</tool>
	<tool picture="trockenrohr.jpg">
		<name>Drying Tube</name>
		<desc>There are reactions which need to be keept free of water. To make this possible one uses a drying tube. In it there is a hygroscopic chemical which will absorb all water.</desc>
	</tool>
	<tool picture="rg-halter.jpg">
		<name>Test tube fastener</name>
		<desc>With a test tube fastener you can easily hold test tubes. If you use a fastener there is a safe distance between the hand and the test tube and the tube can be hot. In particular it is use when you brandisha test tube over an open flame.</desc>
	</tool>
	<tool picture="messzylinder.jpg">
		<name>Graduate</name>
		<desc>In a graduate you can fill amounts of liquids relatively precise. Furthermore a graduate serves to let sack particulate matter. Following you can separate them from the fluid by decanting.</desc>
	</tool>
	<tool picture="thermometer.jpg">
		<name>Thermometer</name>
		<desc>With a thermometer you can determine the temperature. In a laboratory special thermometers are used, which can also be used within acids or bases.</desc>
	</tool>
	<tool picture="ruehrfisch.jpg">
		<name>Magnetic stir bar</name>
		<desc>Magnetic stir bars are chemically nearly unassailable little magnetic bars. Most heaters have a built-in magnet which can rotate. Through this rotation the magnetic stir bars are spinned and the solution the magnetic stir bar is in is homogenised.</desc>
	</tool>
	<tool picture="destillierbruecke.jpg">
		<name>Distillation bridge</name>
		<desc>To separate a mixture you can use distillation among others. The distillation bridge is thereby the way between the two pots. In the one pot there is the mixture to be separated. Caused by heating a gas forms which is lead through the bridge. At the end of the bridge the gas phase is condensed again and drips in a round flask. As a rule  the bridge is cooled by return flow. In addition there is often a thermometer for controlling the temperature on the distillation bridge.</desc>
	</tool>
</tools>
