<tools>
	<tool picture="heizplatte.jpg">
		<name>Heating Coil</name>
		<desc>Heating coils are used to heat flasks and other containers. Multiple heating coils can be connected with a thermometer so that the heat will not exceed a specified temperature. It is possible to use a magnetic field inside the heating coil to stir fluids with a magnetic stirrer. This will homogenize the fluid in terms of temperature and composition.</desc>
	</tool>
	<tool picture="korkring.jpg">
		<name>Cork Ring</name>
		<desc>Large containers like round-bottomed flasks are placed on rings made of cork.</desc>
	</tool>
	<tool picture="tropftrichter.jpg">
		<name>Dropping Funnel</name>
		<desc>A dropping funnel can be used to drop precise amounts of fluid. You can control the dropping speed with a valve.</desc>
	</tool>
	<tool picture="scheidetrichter.jpg">
		<name>Separating Funnel</name>
		<desc>A separating funnel can be used to separate a mixture of fluids by differing density. A valve at the bottom allows you to drain the more dense fluid for transfer to another container.</desc>
	</tool>
	<tool picture="rg-staender.jpg">
		<name>Test Tube Rack</name>
		<desc>This rack comes in handy if you want to test a lot of small amounts of checmicals in a row, or if you want to dry test tubes.</desc>
	</tool>
	<tool picture="">
		<name>Vortexer</name>
		<desc>A vortexer serves to homogenize reagents found in laboratories. The container containing liquid to be homogenized is put on a platform. The platform shakes by rotary agitation up to 3000RPM when a contact sensor is activated. This way extremely small volumes of fluid can be homogenized quickly as well.</desc>
	</tool>
	<tool picture="spritzflasche.jpg">
		<name>Wash Bottle</name>
		<desc>These bottles are used for many purposes. In most laboratories they are usually filled with water, salt acid or other commonly used fluids. They make it easy to apply the fluid if you do not need to measure a precise amount.</desc>
	</tool>
	<tool picture="rotationsverdampfer.jpg">
		<name>Rotary Evaporator</name>
		<desc>A rotary evaporator consists of a round flask in a bath of hot water that is designed to evaporate solvents. The flask is rotated and the solvent collects under a vacuum onto a condenser and drips into a condensate collecting flask. This way solutions can be concentrated or purified. Through an attached vacuum pump the boiling point of the fluid can be decreased.</desc>
	</tool>
	<tool picture="rueckflusskuehler.jpg">
		<name>Reflux Condenser</name>
		<desc>A reflux condenser subjects fluid to a process where a gas produced by heating is collected on the reflux condenser, where it is cooled until it condenses and runs back into the original fluid. Usually it is put on a round bottom flask or several neck flasks.</desc>
	</tool>
	<tool picture="pileusball.jpg">
		<name>Pileusball</name>
		<desc>A pileusball is used to fill pipettes. It produces a negative pressure which makes the fluid go into the pipette. If one lets air back into the ball the fluid will run out of the pipette.</desc>
	</tool>
	<tool picture="rg.jpg">
		<name>Test Tube</name>
		<desc>In test tube a chemist usually performs small reactions. There are a lot of different tubes, for example those with and without grinding.</desc>
	</tool>
	<tool picture="schutzbrille.jpg">
		<name>Protective Goggles</name>
		<desc>Most labarotories insist that everyone is wearing protective goggles: without them, it is too risky to work with most chemicals. Usually, their glass is some kind of specific plastic which protects you from mechanical impacts as well as acids and bases.</desc>
	</tool>
	<tool picture="rundkolben.jpg">
		<name>Round-bottomed Flask</name>
		<desc>A round-bottomed flask is used for a lot of reactions. They can be connected to other items, most of them are grinded. With cork rings they can be placed on a table.</desc>
	</tool>
	<tool picture="vollpipette.jpg">
		<name>Full Pipette</name>
		<desc>Unlike a regular pipette, a full pipette only has one marking for a specific volume.</desc>
	</tool>
	<tool picture="trockenrohr.jpg">
		<name>Drying Tube</name>
		<desc>There are reactions which need to be kept free of water. To make this possible one uses a drying tube. In it there is a hygroscopic chemical which will absorb all water.</desc>
	</tool>
	<tool picture="rg-halter.jpg">
		<name>Test tube fastener</name>
		<desc>With a test tube fastener you can easily hold test tubes. If you use a fastener there is a safe distance between the hand and the test tube and the tube can be hot. In particular it is use when you brandish a test tube over an open flame.</desc>
	</tool>
	<tool picture="messzylinder.jpg">
		<name>Graduate</name>
		<desc>In a graduate you can fill amounts of liquids relatively precisely. Furthermore, a graduate serves to let particulate matter sink. Following this, you can separate it from the fluid by decanting.</desc>
	</tool>
	<tool picture="thermometer.jpg">
		<name>Thermometer</name>
		<desc>With a thermometer you can determine the temperature. In a laboratory special thermometers are used, which can also be used within acids or bases.</desc>
	</tool>
	<tool picture="ruehrfisch.jpg">
		<name>Magnetic stir bar</name>
		<desc>Magnetic stir bars are chemically nearly unassailable little magnetic bars. Most heaters have a built-in magnet which can rotate. Through this rotation the magnetic stir bars are spinned and the solution the magnetic stir bar is in is homogenized.</desc>
	</tool>
	<tool picture="destillierbruecke.jpg">
		<name>Distillation bridge</name>
		<desc>To separate a mixture you can use distillation amongst others. The distillation bridge is thereby the way between the two pots. In the one pot there is the mixture to be separated. Through heating, a gas forms which is lead through the bridge. At the end of the bridge the gas phase is condensed again and drips in a round flask. As a rule, the bridge is cooled by return flow. In addition, there is often a thermometer for controlling the temperature on the distillation bridge.</desc>
	</tool>
	<!-- proofreaders: start here! -->
	<tool picture="kolbenprober.png">
		<name>Syringe</name>
		<desc>A syringe consists of two parts: A glass tube and a punch. Both are normaly made of glass. A gas floats into the glass tube. As the syringe is a closed system the punch has to give way. This can be used to the gasoline volume of an reaktion can be measured.</desc>
	</tool>
	<tool picture="verteiler.jpg">
		<name>Separation Beaker</name>
		<desc>At the four ends of this separation beaker you put four small caps. In a distillation you can turn the beaker by 60 degree after a certain temperatur has been reached. This way, at the end of the distillation all four caps have a specific liquid in it, depending on the boilingpoints of the liquid distilled.</desc>
	</tool>
	<tool picture="brenner.jpg">
		<name>Burner</name>
		<desc>There are several types of burners. The picture shows a Teclu-Burner. Each type has specific uses and varies for example in the temperature which can be reached.</desc>
	</tool>
	<tool picture="abzug.jpg">
		<name>Extractor Hood</name>
		<desc>In most laboratories are extractor hoods. The filter the steam of chemical reaktions and pump the cleaned air outside of the building.</desc>
	</tool>
</tools>
